# Marcos Lopez

District of Columbia | 305-803-0671 | marcintosh87@gmail.com Github | Medium |LinkedIn

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

I am a full-stack software engineer/video producer with 10+ years of working in the health, commercial and education fields in various marketing and internal communication roles. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming, React framework, React-Native mobile development and a background in design and video production. Possess strong skills in teamwork, leadership, project management that can assist any company to achieve positive, forward thinking results.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

SWE: Ruby, Rails, SQL, Posgres, Javascript, React, React-Native, Firebase, HTML, CSS

Design: Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Multimedia: Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Final Cut Pro

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Intra-Stellar - Github | Site Demo (use credentials below) | Video Demo

username: marcos@company.com | password:123456

This is a mono-repo app created to be a SASS, it is an all purpose solution to internal communications for most 50+ employee companies that includes a web and mobile application(iOS/Android). Created with: **Ruby on Rails, React.js, Posgres, React-Native, Material UI, React Native Base, React Native Paper.** 

- Utilized web sockets to implement a real time chat feature with employees
- Used React-Native to create a cross platform mobile version of the web application
- Implemented full CRUD operations for event and news posts
- Provided the ability for employees to engage with each other via user comments

Nimbus- Github | Demo

Username: bugs@123@aol.com | password:123456

A journaling app with authentication that gives the user full CRUD control over their respective journals. Created to monitor a user's mood over a period of time. Created with: **Ruby on Rails, React.js, Posgres, Material UI** 

- Implemented user authentication using Bcrypt gem to encrypt all passwords
- Added privacy capabilities to the submissions that would allow a user to keep some information private
- Provided full create, read, update, and delete capabilities to all journal entries

## Newsbank - Github | Demo

This is a World News website using an external API to generate content (newsapi.org) that also gives users the ability to submit their own community news to provide more visibility to current events in their respective communities. Created with: **Google Firebase**, **React.is**, **Bootstrap**, **Material UI** 

- Used firebase to create user generated content that was able to be voted on to increase visibility
- Leveraged an external API to generate news posts with different genres

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Memorial Healthcare System** Hollywood, FL Web developer/Multimedia Specialist - HR Communications 05/2016 - Present

- Web administrator for Human Resources intranet site serving over 13,000 employees and 5 hospitals
- Assisted in developing internal brand strategies for employee engagement across the system

Archdiocese of Miami Miami, FL Lead Broadcasting/Multimedia Instructor/Marketing Developer 06/2014 -05/2016

- Developed an award winning broadcasting program
- Increased student enrollment via multiple marketing campaigns in the community
- Developed course curriculum and program standards for the journalism/broadcasting section

Florida International University Miami, FL Senior Multimedia Specialist 10/2010 - 06/2014

- Lead in conceptualizing, designing, planning, and producing interactive media materials for FIU Online
- Producing, developing, and editing graphics and camera ready artwork, digital photography, interactive recording and 3D concepts for various formats for marketing

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Washington, DC Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 11/2021 - 02/2022

**Miami International University of Art and Design** Miami, FL Bachelor's in Fine Arts, Visual Effects and Motion Graphics 10/2010